

# Info

# Address:

Chennai, 600004, India

Phone:

+91 9962535683

Email:

j.dhandu@gmail.com

Nationality:

Indian

# Links

(LinkedIn,

Skype)

## Skills

#### **Tableau**

• • • • •

**SPARK** 

• • • • •

Python

• • • •

**Pandas** 

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$ 

**PYTEST** 

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\bullet$ 

**BigQuery** 

• • • •

Data Studio

 $\bullet$ 

# Dhandayuthapani J

DATA ENGINEER

# **Profile**

**Cloud-Data Engineer** - 16+ years of IT experience With Analytics, ETL, Python in GCP technologies.

Cloud platform: Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

**Tools:** ETL transformation in cloud using Functions, SPARK Data Proc clusters | Analytics with Python and Tableau | BigQuery Operations.

**Certifications:** GCP Professional Data Engineer, Tableau Desktop Specialist.

Databases: BigQuery, CloudSQL, DB2.

Operating System: Windows, Linux, Unix.

**Process:** Agile Scrum Methodology and Kanban.

# **Employment History**

### Migration Tech Lead

TATA Consultancy Services LTD

06/2019 - Present, Chennai

- Development of transformation programs to migrate data from in-house Mainframe to Cloud.
- Manage a team and provide guidance in developing POCs for initial data analytics by ingesting streaming data, extracting data from unstructured schema.
- Storing them in cloud appropriate databases and provide exception-handling for errored out records.
- Create metrics-based graphs using Grafana, providing valuable analytics to stakeholders using Data Studio and Tableau.
- Reduced cost (~1.5M\$/week) by eliminating unnecessary servers and consolidating database services.

### Senior A&I Engineer

### TATA Consultancy Services LTD

03/2018 – 05/2019, Chennai

- Create and maintain the fully automated Tableau Dashboards to identify customer transactions which are above threshold limit from causing IMS region crashes.
- Assisted senior level data scientists in the design of ETL processes, including DMI Packages.
- Integrated Data science Forecasting models using BigQuery ML-SQL to Tableau worksheets for designing customer's spending trends.

**Key Achievement:** Solved an ETL issue while following PL/SQL best practices that resulted in an insight that increased client's customer base by 33%.

# SQL

#### Shell



# Agile Methodologies

#### Linux



# **Hobbies**

Solving Problems, Meditation, Playing Chess with my son

# Languages

English



#### Tamil



# **Software Engineer**

# TATA Consultancy Services LTD

09/2008 - 02/2018, Chennai, Chicago

- As an ETL developer participated in pipeline bug fixing.
- Understanding the requirements and change requests.
- Designing code as per the change requests.
- Create reports to validate the required code changes.
- Unit testing, interface testing and implementing database objects for changing the scope towards meeting the objectives of the project.

# **Project Engineer**

# TATA Consultancy Services LTD

06/2005 - 08/2008,

- Coding / conversions of programs that were using VSAM CIF files.
- Generate Technical documents and Job flow documents using DOCGEN and FLOWGEN.
- Unit Testing for defect free deliverables using IPMS.
- Defect analysis and fixing.
- Knowledge transition and documentation of the system.
- Checking the quality of the software and determining its degree of compliance to standards.
- Unit Testing of Enhancements.
- User acceptance test support.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

B.E. (Computer Science) 2000-2004

Madras University, Chennai.